CHARLOTTE LEE

19 Green Knolls Road, Morristown, NJ 07960 <u>charlee@bloomberg.net</u> (718) 663-1370 https://charlee524.github.jo/index.html

SUMMARY

10+ years in developing prototypes of Bloomberg financial applications for the UX team. Experience in designing and developing UI for various cross products such as Fixed Income, Mortgages, FX, Equities, Index Query, Trading Systems, and Alerts. Strong understanding of UI and UX principles.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer / UX Prototyper at Bloomberg LP

12//2007 - Present

- Responsible for building interactive prototypes to validate design concepts for next-generation products.
- Work closely with other members of the UX team to quickly turn interaction and visual design specifications into high-fidelity prototypes (RDE / HTML) that are used by our customers in usability lab (ex: FRD, ALRT, BICO, IQ)
- Develop production applications used by business, engineering, and UX department (ex: BEVO XFNA, FCN, FLE1, BEAM, UXP). Enhance production applications used by clients (ex: XFNA XPT).
- Re-design complex Trading Systems Buy/Sell ticketing UI which supports various security types.

Senior Software Engineer / Software Infrastructure at Bloomberg LP

6/2007 - 12/2007

 Collaborated with engineers and product owners to re-design SMRG/control/GTKF applications into rapid applications.

R&D Electronic Management Systems (EMSX) Requirement at Bloomberg LP

1/2007 - 6/2007

- Interacted with EMS business team to deliver functional requirements for the EMSX, IOI, and Electronic Order Routing teams.
- Protoyped IOI IB concept. Re-designed electronic order routing configuration UI.

UI Designer at Bloomberg LP

12/2005 - 1/2007

- Experienced with designing complex transaction systems including Trading Systems and Core Products. (ex: Seed Dial SPDL, Customized Data Fields CUTS, TOMS Admin Configuration TADM, Loan Search LSRC)
- Managed several projects simultaneously with product owners and engineers to develop UI for new functions:
 Electronic Pool Notification Systems (EPNS), Middle Office Monitor (MOM),
- Client visit swith sales rep to understand user workflow.
- Partnership with engineers to redesign core products (Equity, Fixed Income, community)

Trading Systems Application Developer / Team Lead at Bloomberg LP

1/1998 - 12/2005

- Team Lead for Trading Systems Crystal Reports and Trade History Reports. Managed all new enhancement request of new report from business.
- Experienced with all phases of SDLC including designing, implementation, testing, and project management.
- Implemented and deployed offline tasks to generate report data.

TRAINING

Interaction 17 IXDA17 Conference

Data Visualization

Agile/Scrum Methodology/Scrum Master Training

The Science and Art of Effective Web and Application Design

Nielsen Norman Group NN/g Conference 2011: Usability Week 2011

Navigation Design, Patterns for Web Design

Usability on Mobile Devices

Touchscreen Application Usability

Structuring and Organizing Web-Based Information

Usability Testing

EDUCATION

New York University Completed 40 credits towards MS in Management and Systems **University of New York at Buffalo**, BS in MIS and Finance

1997 – 2002 1997

SKILLS

- Rapid Prototyping
- RDE, R+, Datalayer
- Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, C, C#, FORTRAN